is jkoch21@usf.edu
 is (631) 372-1384
 is Tampa, FL

# **Jonathan Koch**

https://jonathanzkoch.dev/home

https://linkedin.com/in/jonathanzkoch/ 
https://github.com/Johnnykoch02/

https://linktr.ee/Johnnykoch02/

**OVERVIEW** 

Languages: Python, C & C++ (including CUDA, OpenCL, & oneDNN), C#, Java, RISC-V, Julia, Lua, JavaScript, Perl, R

Competencies: ROS, Actor-Critic, Tensor Libraries & Math, Sockets, NumPy, Linux, Computer Networking, 2D & 3D Physics and Simulation Engines
Research Background: Robotics & AI; Object Manipulation, Audio & Image Processing, Probabilistic Robotics, Reinforcement Learning, Transformers
Interests: Predictive Models, Algorithmic Trading, Multi-Agent Learning & AI, Generative Models, Data Science, Acoustic Guitar, Piano, BJJ

#### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Concentration in Robotics and AI

**Cumulative GPA:** 

University of South Florida College of Engineering, Tampa, FL

3.7/4.0

Courses Taken: Automata Theory, Intro to AI, Mobile Robotics, Natural Language Processing, Linear Algebra

Fall 2020 - Spring 2024

**EXPERIENCE** 

## Software Engineering R&D Co/Op

May 2022 - Present

CAE USA Research and Development Facility https://cae.com/

Tampa FL

- Development of Windows and Linux lab environments of computer system networks for simulation and hardware testing.
- Oversaw development of specialized Linux-based driver software used for proprietary Sim-based interactive systems.

#### Research Scientist

Fall 2021 - Present

Robot Perception and Action Laboratory, *University of South Florida*, <a href="https://rpal.cse.usf.edu/">https://rpal.cse.usf.edu/</a>

Tampa FL

- Research in robotic <u>object manipulation</u> through supervised and reinforcement learning; construct and pretrain a transformer network tasked for encoding spatial information, explore methods for improving accuracy of a policy.
- Document and communicate results amongst lab members and incorporate recorded findings into academic publishing.

## Senior Coding Coach and Instructor

**Fall 2021 – Summer 2023** 

 $the Coder School\ Tampa\ \underline{\it https://github.com/theCoderSchoolTampa/CoderSchoolAI}$ 

Tampa FL

- Instructed young aspiring software developers in Computer Science concepts and brought their creativity to life
- *CoderSchoolAI*: Spearheaded an initiative for effectively delivering theoretical CS concepts involving Agent AI in a simpler and more digestible interface for kids. Developed an educational program built on-top of a Python Library designed to remove complexity of Agent AI concepts. Introduced search-based and neural network-based approaches for building AI agents. Guided the development of agents through classic and learning-based methods. (*Snake in Python*)

#### Vice Chair; AI Group, VEX Robotics

Fall 2020 - Present

USF IEEE Student Chapter

Tampa FL

- Organize and oversee Professional Development events/forums, plan our Spring/Fall Picnics and Banquets, introduce new students and act as the main POC for all USF students interested in joining IEEE's Technical Clubs and Teams.
- Founded AI Group; built mini compute cluster for simulation and training of neural networks, leadership in AI projects
- Created programming team for VEX Robotics, introduce new programing techniques based in RL and simulation

#### **PROJECTS**

#### CoderSchoolAI (pip install CoderSchoolAI)

May 2023 - Present

 $\underline{https://github.com/theCoderSchoolTampa/CoderSchoolAI/blob/master/README.md}$ 

(Demo) <u>https://youtu.be/\_cpspql8Chw?si=IlI8mxfdjF8rDdph</u>

- Neural Network API and Reinforcement learning library built on-top of Python & PyTorch designed for beginners.
- MDP implementation in 10 lines of code, created basic API for developing many-to-many DNN function approximators, various data and tensor utilities for efficient data manipulation, implementation of PPO, DQN, and DDPG algorithms.
- Used in my robotics research in RPAL. Continuously developing and expanding capabilities. Find it on PyPi.

# Virtual Assistant

**August 2022 - Present** 

https://github.com/Johnnykoch02/VirtualAssistant/blob/main/README.md

(Demo) https://www.instagram.com/reel/Cu2ECSlPcfw/

- Expand the abilities of a computer's ability to solve user's problems via interpretation of natural language.
- Keyword Detection via Sequence Modeling and LSTM Network to avoid Speech-To-Text Charges from Google ♥
- By prompting the system, it will retrieve what it thinks your intentions are and execute a sequence to solve the problem.

# **Autonomous Robotics Motion Library**

August 2021 - Present

https://github.com/Johnnykoch02/BullBot

(Competition Video) https://www.instagram.com/reel/CdJ00oyvc0V/

- Software Library written for TerriBull Robotics Team for full autonomous capability and task implementation.
  - Led a research project in modeling our robots in a simulated environment designed for learning to solve our dynamic time-based objectives. Utilization of offline and online reinforcement learning algorithms (DDPG+HER).
- Introspected the challenges of learning in multi-agent systems to improve my own understandings of intelligence.